# Chiho Choi, Ph.D.

## CONTACT INFROMATION

Honda Research Institute USA Inc. Website 70 Rio Robles, San Jose, CA 95134 LinkedIn chihochoi@outlook.com Google Scholar

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests span the fields of computer vision, machine learning, and robotics, focusing on understanding and prediction of human behavior in highly interactive environments. In this area, I build a new perspective for the safe operation of autonomous systems designed to cooperate with humans.

• Behavior Reasoning

- Motion Prediction
- Activity Forecasting
- Relational Inference

- Uncertainty Modeling
- Interactive Planning
- Human Pose Prediction Pose Estimation

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Honda Research Institute (HRI) USA

San Jose, CA, USA

**Senior Scientist** 

July 2021 – Present

• Leading multiple projects on understanding of human action, intention, and future behavior.

**Scientist** 

February 2018 – June 2021

• Worked on recognition, reasoning, and prediction of human states and behaviors in multi-agent interacting environments.

HERE Technologies

Chicago, IL, USA

Intern May 2017 – August 2017

- Worked on traffic scene understanding (detection and recognition) for automated driving.
- Proposed a solution to learn from imbalanced data for generic machine learning systems.
- Supervisor: Dr. Xiang Ma and Prof. Xin Chen

## **EDUCATION**

Purdue University West Lafayette, IN, USA

## Ph.D., Electrical and Computer Engineering

January 2018

- Specialization: deep learning, 3D vision, recognition, tracking
- Committee members: Karthik Ramani, Stanley H. Chan, Mireille Boutin, Jeffrey M. Siskind

University of Southern California

Los Angeles, CA, USA

M.S., Electrical Engineering May 2013

- Specialization: 3D shape matching, registration
- Advisor: Prof. Suya You, Department of Computer Science

Seoul, Korea Hanyang University

# **B.S.**, Electronics and Computer Engineering

February 2011

• Minor: Mechanical Engineering

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

## **Refereed Papers**

- [C18] H. Girase\*, H. Gang\*, S. Malla, J. Li, A. Kanehara, K. Mangalam, and C. Choi. "LOKI: Long Term and Key Intentions for Trajectory Prediction". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)* 2021, to appear.
- [C17] J. Li, F. Yang, H. Ma, S. Malla, M. Tomizuka, and C. Choi. "RAIN: Reinforced Hybrid Attention Inference Network for Motion Forecasting". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)* 2021, to appear.
- [C16] H. Ma\*, Y. Sun\*, J. Li, M. Tomizuka, and C. Choi. "Continual Multi-agent Interaction Behavior Prediction with Conditional Generative Memory". *IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)*, to appear.
- [C15] C. Choi\*, J. H. Choi\*, J. Li, and S. Malla "Shared Cross-Modal Trajectory Prediction for Autonomous Driving". *In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)* 2021, Oral presentation (4.2% acceptance rate). *arXiv:* 2011.08436
- [C14] S. Malla, C. Choi, and B. Dariush "Social-STAGE: Spatio-Temporal Multi-Modal Future Trajectory Forecast". In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2021. arXiv: 2011.04853
- [C13] J. Li, F. Yang, M. Tomizuka, and C. Choi. "EvolveGraph: Multi-Agent Trajectory Prediction with Dynamic Relational Reasoning". *In Proceedings of the Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)* 2020. arXiv: 2003.13924
- [C12] C. Choi, S. Malla, A. Patil, and J. H. Choi. "DROGON: A Trajectory Prediction Model based on Intention-Conditioned Behavior Reasoning". *In Proceedings of the Conference on Robot Learning* (CoRL) 2020. arXiv:1908.00024
- [C11] I. Dwivedi, S. Malla, B. Dariush, and C. Choi. "SSP: Single Shot Future Trajectory Prediction". In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS) 2020. arXiv: 2004.05846
- [C10] S. Malla, B. Dariush, and C. Choi. "TITAN: Future Forecast using Action Priors". *In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)* 2020, Oral presentation (5.7% acceptance rate). *arXiv*:2003.13886
- [C9] S. Bae, D. Saxena, A. Nakhaei, C. Choi, K. Fujimura, and S. Moura. "Cooperation-Aware Lane Change Maneuver in Dense Traffic based on Model Predictive Control with Recurrent Neural Network". *In Proceedings of the American Control Conference (ACC)* 2020. arXiv:1909.05665
- [C8] C. Choi and B. Dariush. "Looking to Relations for Future Trajectory Forecast". In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2019. arXiv: 1905.08855
- [C7] C. Choi and B. Dariush. "Learning to Infer Relations for Future Trajectory Forecast". *In the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshops 2019.*
- [C6] Y. Yao, M. Xu, C. Choi, D. Crandall, E. Atkins, and B. Dariush. "Egocentric Vision-based Future Vehicle Localization for Intelligent Driving Assistance Systems". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)* 2019.
- [C5] M. Liu, F. Yao, C. Choi, A. Sinha, and K. Ramani. "Deep Learning 3D Shapes Using Alt-az Anisotropic 2-Sphere Convolution". *In Proceedings of the International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)* 2019.
- [C4] C. Choi, S. Kim, and K. Ramani. "Learning Hand Articulations by Hallucinating Heat Distribution". In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2017.
- [C3] C. Choi, S. H. Yoon, C. N. Chen, and K. Ramani. "Robust Hand Pose Estimation during the Interaction with an Unknown Object". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)* 2017.
- [C2] C. Choi\*, A. Sinha\*, and K. Ramani (\* Co-first Author, order changed for emphasis). "DeepHand: Robust Hand Pose Estimation by Completing a Matrix Imputed with Deep Features". *In Proceedings of*

- the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2016.
- [C1] C. Choi, A. Sinha, J. H. Choi, S. Jang, and K. Ramani. "A Collaborative Filtering Approach to Real-Time Hand Pose Estimation". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision* (ICCV) 2015.

## **Non-Refereed Papers**

- [T4] S. Su, C. Peng, J. Shi, and C. Choi. "Potential Field: Interpretable and Unified Representation for Trajectory Prediction". *November 2019. arXiv:1911.07414*
- [T3] S. Malla, I. Dwivedi, B. Dariush, and C. Choi. "NEMO: Future Object Localization Using Noisy Ego Priors". *September 2019. arXiv:1909.08150*
- [T2] C. Choi, S. Kim, J. H. Choi, and K. Ramani. "Embedding Compressive Layers in Deep Neural Networks". *Technical Report, Purdue University, May 2017*.
- [T1] C. Choi and S. You. "Dense and Reliable Shape Matching using 3D Particle Filtering". *Technical Report, University of Southern California, May 2013.*

#### **Thesis**

[D1] C. Choi. "Computational Learning for Hand Pose Estimation". Ph.D. Dissertation, Purdue University, Jan 2018.

## PATENT APPLICATIONS

- [P21] J. Li, H. Gang, H. Ma, and C. Choi. "System and Method for Important Object Identification with Semi-Supervised Learning". Application pending.
- [P20] H. Girase, H. Gang, S. Malla, J. Li, A. Kanehara, and C. Choi. "System and Method for Providing Long Term Key Intentions for Trajectory Prediction". Application pending.
- [P19] H. Ma, J. Li, and C. Choi. "System and Method for Completing Continual Multi-Agent Trajectory Forecasting". Application pending.
- [P18] C. Choi, S. Malla, and S. Bae. "System and Method for Completing Trajectory from Agent-Augmented Environments". Application pending.
- [P17] J. Li and C. Choi. "System and Method for Reinforced Hybrid Attention for Motion Forecasting". Application pending.
- [P16] S. Malla, C. Choi, and B. Dariush. "System and Method for Providing Social-Stage Spatio-Temporal Multi-Modal Future Forecasting". Application pending.
- [P15] C. Choi. "System and Method for Shared Cross-Modal Trajectory Prediction". Application pending.
- [P14] J. Li and C. Choi. "Systems and Methods for Heterogeneous Multi-Agent Multi-Modal Trajectory Prediction with Evolving Interaction Graphs". Application pending.
- [P13] I. Dwivedi, S. Malla, C. Choi, and Behzad Dariush. "System for Single Shot Prediction using Composite Fields and Method Thereof". Application pending.
- [P12] S. Malla, C. Choi, and Behzad Dariush. "System and Method for Future Forecasting using Action Priors". No. 16/913260
- [P11] S. Su and C. Choi. "System and Method for Providing an Interpretable and Unified Representation for Trajectory Prediction". No. 16/911661
- [P10] A. Nakhaei, K. Fujimura, C. Choi, S. Bae, D. Saxena. "System and Method for Providing Cooperation-Aware Lane Change Control in Dense Traffic". No. 16/844331
- [P9] S. Malla and C. Choi. "System and Method for Providing Future Object Localization". No. 16/828343
- [P8] C. Choi. "Trajectory Prediction". US 11/087477
- [P7] Y. Yao, M. Xu, C. Choi, and B. Dariush. "System and Method for Egocentric-vision based Future

Vehicle Localization". Publication No. 16/386964

- [P6] C. Choi. "Methods and Apparatuses for Future Trajectory Forecast". US 11/062141
- [P5] X. Chen, X. Ma, S. Sood, and C. Choi. "Semi-automatic Training Data Selection based on High-dimensional Data Projection to Subspaces". Application pending.
- [P4] X. Chen, X. Ma, S. Sood, and C. Choi. "Deep Neural Machine for Lane Marking Style Classification based on Unwrapped Perspective Images". Application pending.
- [P3] X. Chen, X. Ma, S. Sood, and C. Choi. "Deep Neural Machine for Lane Marking Color and Material Classification based on Image Patches". Application pending.
- [P2] A. Sinha, C. Choi, J. H. Choi, and K. Ramani. "Method of training neural networks for hand pose detection". US 10/503270
- [P1] A. Sinha, C. Choi, J. H. Choi, and K. Ramani. "Method and System for Hand Pose Estimation". US 10/318008

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

## **Students Supervised**

• Reza Ghoddoosian (Ph.D.), from University of Texas, Arlington	May 2021 – Present
• Ramtin Hosseini (Ph.D.), from Tufts University	May 2021 – Present
• Hengbo Ma (Ph.D.), from University of California, Berkeley	January 2021 – Present
• Harshayu Girase (M.S.), from University of California, Berkeley	January 2021 – Present
• Jiachen Li (Ph.D.), from University of California, Berkeley	September 2019 – May 2021
• Crane He Chen (Ph.D.), from Johns Hopkins University	January 2021 – April 2021
• Shan Su (Ph.D.), from University of Pennsylvania	July 2019 – December 2020
• Sangjae Bae (Ph.D.), from University of California, Berkeley	May 2020 – August 2020
	June 2019 – September 2019
• Yu Yao (Ph.D.), from University of Michigan	May 2018 – August 2018

#### **Teaching Assistant**

Purdue University

January 2015 – May 2015

ME 444: Computer-aided Design and Rapid Prototyping

Introduction to advanced computer-aided design for product design, modeling, and prototyping.

• University of Southern California

August 2012 – December 2012

CSCI 588 (graduate-level course): Specification and Design of User Interface Software

A design and implementation of user interface software relating to human/computer interaction.

## INVITED TALKS

Guest Lecturer, Purdue University

December 2017

• Introduction to Pose Estimation – Probabilistic models in computer vision

#### **ACADEMIC SERVICES**

#### **Organizing Committee**

• Co-organizer, Workshop on *Multi-Agent Interaction and Relational Reasoning* in conjunction with ICCV 2021

#### **Publication Committee**

• Honda Research Institute USA

February 2020 - Present

#### **Program Committee / Reviewer**

• International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2021, 2022

- IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV) 2021, 2022
- Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2020, 2021
- IEEE International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS) 2021
- IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2019, 2021
- International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2021
- IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2018, 2019, 2020, 2021
- Association for Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2020, 2021
- Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV) 2018, 2020
- European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) 2020
- IEEE Intelligent Vehicles Symposium (IV) 2020
- ACM CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI) 2019
- IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)
- IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Vehicles (T-IV)
- IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (T-IP)
- IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (T-MM)

## **HORNORS**

National Science and Technology Scholarship from *Ministry of Education, Science and Technology*, Korea 2003 - 2010

# **MEDIA COVERAGE**

- Looking to Relations for Future Trajectory Forecast, ICCV Daily Magazine, October 30, 2019.
- AI Can Predict the Future Location of Vehicles, NVIDIA NEWS Center, September 27, 2018.
- Freeing Our Fingers: Handing Over VR's Toughest Challenge to GPUs, NVIDIA Blog, August 24, 2016.
- AI and VR: New Experiments at Purdue University, ENGINEERING.com, June 30, 2016
- DeepHand motion tracking enters the VR arms race, New Atlas, June 23, 2016
- New tool for virtual and augmented reality uses 'deep learning', Purdue News, June 22, 2016.

#### REFERENCES

Available Upon Request